Guide to the Meyer Schapiro Collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V: Research files, 1930s-1990s
  - Subseries: V.4: Research card files, 1930s-1980s
    - Vassily Kandinsky (Box 315)
    - Kazimir Malevitch and Russian art (Box 315)
    - Impressionism (Box 315)
    - Édouard Manet (Box 315)
    - Edgar Degas (Box 315)
    - Camille Pissarro (Box 316)
    - Pierre-August Renoir (Box 316)
    - Vincent van Gogh (Box 316)
    - Paul Gauguin (Box 316)
    - James Ensor (Box 316)
    - Ferdinand Hodler (Box 316)
    - Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec (Box 316)
    - Pierre Bonnard and Edouard Vuillard (Box 316)
    - Odilon Redon (Box 316)
    - Modern art (Box 317)
    - 19th century (Box 317)
    - Surrealism (Box 317)
    - American (Box 317)
    - Modern realism (Box 317)
    - Modern sculpture (Box 317)
    - Modern architecture (Box 317)
    - Abraham and Isaac (Box 317)
    - Ruthwell Cross (Box 317)
    - Muscipula Diaboli (Box 317)
    - Auxerre manuscripts (Box 317)
    - Post-Impressionism (Box 318)
    - 19th and 20th century painting (Box 318)
    - Words and pictures (Box 318)
    - Paul Cézanne (Box 318)
    - Apples of Cézanne (Box 318)
    - [Value and proportion] (Box 319)
    - Criteria (Box 319)
    - Hierarchy of value (Box 319)
    - On Lewis (Box 319)
    - Style (Box 319)
    - Style and theory of form (Box 319)
    - Form (Box 319)
    - Expression (Box 319)
    - Value (Box 319)
    - Interpretation (Box 319)
    - Classification (Box 320)
    - Interpretation, meaning, iconography (Box 320)
    - Bibliography (Box 320)
    - Theory of art (Box 320)
    - Semiotics (Box 320)
    - Language (Box 320)
    - Theory of language (Box 320)
    - Theory (Gestalt theory) (Box 320)
    - Cézanne and the philosophers (Box 321)
    - Words and pictures (Box 321)
    - Filippo Brunelleschi (Box 321)
    - [Artists] (Box 322)
    - Art as knowledge (Box 322)
    - Classification (Box 322)
    - Classification and styles (Box 322)
    - Style (Box 322)
    - Psychology of art (Box 322)
    - Interpretation (Box 322)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 323)
    - Theory (Box 323)
    - Dwarfs and giants (Box 323)
    - Wolvinius (Box 323)
    - Enoch (Box 324)
    - Pablo Picasso, Cubism, and Henri Matisse (Box 324)
    - Guernica (Box 324)
    - Meaning [Guernica] (Box 325)
    - Meaning, content [Guernica] (Box 325)
    - Before Guernica, January-April, 1937 (Box 325)
    - Preparatory drawings [Guernica] (Box 325)
    - Sketches, studies, and stages [Guernica] (Box 325)
    - Pablo Picasso's Guernica, states of canvas (Box 325)
    - Style and structure [Guernica] (Box 325)
    - Politics after 1944 [Guernica] (Box 325)
    - Pablo Picasso and Eugenio d'Ors (Box 325)
    - Dream and lies of Franco (Box 325)
    - Pegasus (Box 325)
    - Pablo Picasso, texts and images, personal references, and biography (Box 325)
    - Pablo Picasso's Guernica (Box 325)
    - Cubism and science (Box 326)
    - Giambattista Vico (Box 326)
    - Views on art and science, 19th and 20th centuries (Box 326)
    - Albert Einstein II (Box 326)
    - Albert Einstein II: the organismic interpretation (Box 326)
    - Selected Papers IV (Box 327)
    - Aby Warburg (Box 327)
    - Giambattista Vico (Box 327)
    - [Albert Einstein] (Box 328)
    - Siegfried Kracauer (Box 329)
    - Origins of art (Box 329)
    - Anglo-Saxon (Box 329)
    - Rodez/Silos, Romanesque (Box 329)
    - Joseph's story, Maximillian's chair, working notes (Box 329)
    - Frick "Flagellation" (Box 329)
    - An English illuminated psalrter/Morgan manuscript Glazier (Box 329)
    - Crossed nimbus (Box 329)
    - Leonardo da Vinci and Sigmund Freud (Box 329)
    - Eugène Fromentin (Box 329)
    - Bede-Hiberno-Saxon (Box 330)
    - Glazier manuscript (Box 330)
    - Hiberno-Saxon (Box 330)
    - Exposition Universelle (Box 330)
    - Bibliographies of Romanesque sculpture (Box 330)
    - Bibliographies and personal notes (Box 330)
    - [Bibliographies and personal notes, continued] (Box 331)
    - Personal notes (Box 331)
    - Bibliographies (Box 331)
    - Modern Architecture (Box 331)
    - Abstraction (Box 332)
    - Study of art history (Box 332)
    - Paul Cèzanne / Marc Chagall (Box 332)
    - Doubting Thomas, early Christian, Hiberno-Saxon, Hieroglyphics (Box 332)
    - Icarus and Daedelus (Box 332)
    - Impressionism (Box 332)
    - Carl Jung (Box 332)
    - Perpsective (Box 332)
    - Philosophy in painting (Box 332)
    - Pablo Picasso and Cubism (Box 332)
    - Political, Socialism (Box 332)
    - Representation (Box 332)
    - Romanesque (Box 332)
    - Semiotics (Box 332)
    - Words and pictures (Box 332)
    - On authors, refugee scholars (Box 332)
    - Personal, auto-biographical notes (Box 332)
    - Shadow (Box 332)
    - Color (Box 332)
    - Religion (Box 332)
    - Bibliographies (Box 333)
    - Personal/publishing (Box 333)
    - Paul Cézanne (Box 333)
    - Primitive art (Box 334)
    - Greek (Box 334)
    - Coptic (Box 334)
    - Etruscan (Box 334)
    - Roman (Box 334)
    - Manuscripts (Box 334)
    - Early Christian (Box 334)
    - Byzantine (Box 334)
    - General medieval (Box 334)
    - Hiberno-Saxon (Box 334)
    - Romanesque (Box 334)
    - Castelseprio (Box 334)
    - Auxerre (Box 334)
    - Beaulieu (Box 334)
    - Moissac (Box 334)
    - Silos (Box 334)
    - Souillac (Box 334)
    - Islamic (Box 334)
    - Gothic (Box 334)
    - Renaissance (Box 334)
    - 17th century Nicolas Poussin (Box 334)
    - Rembrandt van Rijn (Box 334)
    - 18th and 19th German painting (Box 334)
    - Jean-August-Dominique Ingres (Box 334)
    - Eugène Delacroix (Box 334)
    - Gustave Courbet (Box 334)
    - Edouard Manet (Box 334)
    - Paul Cézanne (Box 334)
    - 20th Century (Box 334)
    - Henri Matisse (Box 334)
    - Pablo Picasso (Box 334)
    - Surrealism (Box 334)
    - Cubism (Box 334)
    - Paul Klee (Box 334)
    - Germanic art and expression (Box 334)
    - Russia (Box 334)
    - Piet Mondrian (Box 334)
    - Modern architecture (Box 334)
    - Modern sculpture (Box 334)
    - Abstract art (Box 334)
    - Secular iconography (Box 334)
    - Alois Riegl (Box 334)
    - Museums/Collections (Box 334)
    - Projects (Box 334)
    - Art teaching (Box 334)
    - Content (Box 334)
    - Ornament / art teaching (Box 334)
    - Perception (Box 334)
    - Children's drawing (Box 334)
    - Perspective (Box 334)
    - Portraiture (Box 334)
    - Theory (Box 334)
    - Sociology of art (Box 335)
    - Value (Box 335)
    - Theory (Box 335)
    - Selected Papers IV (Box 336)
    - Lectures (Box 336)
    - Script (Box 336)
    - Work and personal (Box 336)
    - Moissac, Merode, Bernard Berenson, Medieval city, Pablo Picasso, Political, Impressionism (Box 336)
    - Pablo Picasso, woman with a fan (Box 336)
    - Sigmund Freud and Luca Signorelli (Box 337)
    - General -- Unsorted (Box 337)
    - General -- Unsorted (Box 651)
    - General -- Unsorted (Box 652)
  - Subseries: V.5: Research notes, 1920s-1990s
    Subseries: V.5 contains the heart of Schapiro's research files and includes notes from a wide range of subjects. Although Schapiro was scrupulous about creating research notes, he was less concerned with how the notes were stored and filed. As a result, many of his research files contained a plethora of material that was not related to each other in either content or subject. As a result, material was organized and grouped according to the subject of the contents. For notes relating to the illumination of books and manuscripts, Schapiro organized material either by repository in which the codex is located or by region from which it was created. Physical folders indicate manuscript numbers which are represented in the file. Material related to illumination of books and manuscripts were reproduced in the 2007 publication Meyer Schapiro abroad: letters to Lillian and travel notebooks.
    Schapiro wrote many research notes that are interrelated with other subjects in the collection. In this light, material in this subseries can be used in conjunction with records in other series of this collection.
    Unlike Subseries: V.4, files in Subseries V.5 are organized by subject headings that are derived from the Library of Congress Subject Headings based on the contents of the records housed in the files. In the event that Schapiro’s own subject heading are too unique to be mapped to a Library of Congress Subject Heading, his own titles were utilized.
    - Albers, Josef, circa 1960s (Box 338, Folder 1)
    - Animals as artists -- Monkeys, circa 1950s (Box 338, Folder 2)
    - Antisemitism, 1969 (Box 338, Folder 3)
    - Architecture -- Details, bulbous domes, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 338, Folder 4)
    - Architecture -- Details, double shell domes, circa 1930s (Box 338, Folder 5)
    - Architecture, Early Christian, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 338, Folder 6)
    - Architecture, Modern, 1948 February (Box 338, Folder 7)
      (Notes are on the symposium "What is happening to modern architecture?" held at the Museum of Modern Art. Accompanied by the catalog for the symposium)
      - Architecture, Romanesque, circa 1930s, (2 Folders) (Box 338, Folder 8 to 9)
      - Art, 1970s-1980s (Box 338, Folder 10)
      - Art, Abstract, circa 1930s-1960s, (8 Folders) (Box 338, Folder 11 to 18)
      - Art, Early Christian, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 338, Folder 19)
      - Art, Early Christian and Modern art, circa 1950s (Box 338, Folder 20)
      - Art, Early Renaissance -- Ocaña (Spain), circa 1930s (Box 338, Folder 21)
      - Art, Medieval, circa 1920s-1940s, (3 Folders) (Box 662, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Art, Medieval and Romanesque -- Decoration and ornament -- Animal forms, 1940s (Box 662, Folder 4)
      - Art, Medieval -- France, circa 1950s (Box 662, Folder 5)
      - Art, Medieval -- Human beings -- Migration, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 662, Folder 6)
      - Art, Medieval -- Labors of the month, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 662, Folder 7)
      - Art, Modern, 1930s-1960, (3 Folders) (Box 339, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Art, Modern -- Artists, circa 1960s (Box 339, Folder 4)
      - Art, Modern -- Religious aspects, circa 1960s (Box 339, Folder 5)
      - Art, Romanesque, circa 1930s (Box 339, Folder 6)
      - Art, Romanesque -- Church history, circa 1970s (Box 339, Folder 7)
      - Art, Romanesque -- Doorways -- Animal forms, circa 1960s (Box 339, Folder 8)
      - Art, Romanesque -- Fighting figures, 1930s (Box 339, Folder 9)
      - Art, Romanesque -- Mural painting and decoration, 1930s, (2 Folders) (Box 339, Folder 10 to 11)
      - Art, Romanesque -- Spain, 1940s-1970s, (2 Folders) (Box 339, Folder 12 to 13)
      - Art, Romanesque -- Spain -- Alter cross of King Fernando and Queen Sancha, 1063 circa 1930s-1950s (Box 339, Folder 14)
      - Art, Sassanid, circa 1930s (Box 339, Folder 15)
      - Art -- History, circa 1930s-1940s, (2 Folders) (Box 339, Folder 16 to 17)
      - Art -- History -- Historiography, circa 1930s (Box 339, Folder 18)
      - Art -- History -- Teaching, 1940s-1960s (Box 339, Folder 19)
      - Art -- Methodology, 1950s (Box 340, Folder 1)
      - Art criticism, 1940s-1960s (Box 340, Folder 2)
        (Includes typescripts of Schapiro's own poetry)
        - Art nouveau, circa 1940s (Box 340, Folder 3)
        - Art and race, circa 1930s (Box 340, Folder 4)
        - Art and science, circa 1930s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 340, Folder 5 to 6)
          (Material in file 4 is sequentially paginated by Schapiro)
        - Art and society, circa 1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 340, Folder 7 to 8)
        - Art and state, 1940s-1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 340, Folder 9 to 10)
        - Bacon, Francis, 1963 (Box 340, Folder 11)
          (Notes relate to a Francis Bacon exhibition at the Guggenheim museum in November, 1963)
        - Basilica di S. Vitale (Ravenna, Italy), circa 1940s (Box 340, Folder 12)
        - Barr, Alfred Hamilton -- Publications, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 340, Folder 13)
        - Baudelaire, Charles, circa 1940s (Box 340, Folder 14)
        - Benjamin, Walter, 1920s-1980s (Box 340, Folder 15)
        - Berenson, Bernard, 1980s-1990s (Box 340, Folder 16)
        - Bergman, Robet, 1990s (Box 340, Folder 17)
        - Bernini, Gian Lorenzo, circa 1940s (Box 340, Folder 18)
        - Berzé-la-Ville, France. Chapelle des moines de Cluny, 1930s (Box 340, Folder 19)
        - Bezalel (Biblical figure), 1980s-1990s (Box 340, Folder 20)
        - Biel, Joseph, circa 1950s (Box 340, Folder 21)
        - Blind artists, circa 1950s (Box 340, Folder 22)
          (Notes are chiefly on Ludwig Münz and Victor Lowenfeld's stuy "Die plastische arbeiten blinder)
        - Blume, Peter, 1937 (Box 340, Folder 23)
        - Boas, Franz, circa 1930s (Box 340, Folder 24)
        - Boas, Franz and primitive art, circa 1930s (Box 340, Folder 25)
        - Book of Kells, circa 1960s (Box 340, Folder 26)
        - Breton, André, 1934-1955 (Box 340, Folder 27)
          (Includes Breton's 1934 publication Qu'est-ce que le surréalisme?"
        - Breton, André and Leon Trotsky, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 340, Folder 28)
        - Bruegel, Pieter, I, 1930s-1950s (Box 340, Folder 29)
        - Buildings -- War damage, 1940s-1950s (Box 340, Folder 30)
        - Caravaggio, Michelangelo Merisi da, 1950s-1960s (Box 341, Folder 1)
        - Cathédrale de Chartres -- Towers, circa 1930s-1940s, (3 Folders) (Box 341, Folder 2 to 4)
        - Cézanne, Paul, 1940s-1960s, (6 Folders) (Box 341, Folder 5 to 10)
        - Cézanne, Paul and Vincent van Gogh, comparisons and differences, circa 1940-1960s (Box 341, Folder 10)
        - Chardin, Jean-Siméon, 1940s (Box 341, Folder 11)
        - Christian art and symbolism, circa 1930s, (3 Folders) (Box 341, Folder 12 to 14)
        - Cinema, 1930s-1940s (Box 663, Folder 1)
        - Cinema and painting, 1930s-1940s (Box 663, Folder 2)
        - Circumcision of Christ and nudity in Renaissance art, circa 1950s (Box 663, Folder 3)
        - Cities and towns, Medieval, circa 1930s-1960s, (3 Folders) (Box 663, Folder 4 to 6)
        - Color, 1930s-1990s, (2 Folders) (Box 663, Folder 7 to 8)
        - Color theory and Impressionism, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 342, Folder 1)
          (Notes were created by Miriam Schild Bunim)
        - Communism, 1930s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 342, Folder 2 to 3)
        - Communism and art, 1930s-1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 342, Folder 4 to 5)
        - Computer art, 1975 (Box 342, Folder 6)
        - Coomaraswamy, Ananda Kentish, 1930s (Box 342, Folder 7)
        - Corot, Jean-Baptiste-Camille, 1940s-1990s, (7 Folders) (Box 342, Folder 8 to 14)
        - Croce, Benedetto, circa 1930s (Box 342, Folder 15)
        - Cubism, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 342, Folder 16)
        - Cubism and collage, 1938 (Box 342, Folder 17)
        - Dagulf psalter, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 342, Folder 18)
        - Daumier, Honoré, 1940s-1990s (Box 342, Folder 19)
        - Degas, Edgar, 1938-1948 (Box 342, Folder 20)
        - Delacroix, Eugène, 1940s-1980s (Box 342, Folder 21)
        - Deschamps, Paul, circa 1930s (Box 342, Folder 22)
        - Dewey, John, circa 1930s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 343, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Dreams, circa 1940s (Box 343, Folder 3)
        - Duchamp, Marcel, 1980s (Box 343, Folder 4)
        - Echternach gospels and Islamic art, 1960s-1990s (Box 343, Folder 5)
        - Education, 1970s (Box 343, Folder 6)
        - Eighteen nineties, circa 1940s, (2 Folders) (Box 343, Folder 7 to 8)
        - Ensor, James, 1930s-1940s (Box 343, Folder 9)
        - Evangelists -- Portraits, circa 1940s, (2 Folders) (Box 343, Folder 10 to 11)
        - Excavations (Archeology) -- Russia, 1930s (Box 343, Folder 12)
        - Expression, 1970s-1980s (Box 343, Folder 13)
        - Fauvism, 1940s-1950s (Box 344, Folder 1)
        - Fogg Art Museum, 1930s (Box 344, Folder 2)
        - Form (Aesthetics), 1930s (Box 344, Folder 3)
        - Futurism (Art), circa 1940s (Box 344, Folder 4)
        - Gauguin, Paul, 1940s-1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 344, Folder 5 to 6)
        - Geisteswissenschaft and Naturwiss, circa 1950s (Box 344, Folder 7)
        - Genetic method, theory and history, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 344, Folder 8)
        - Géricault, Théodore, circa 1950s (Box 344, Folder 9)
        - Gestalt theory, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 344, Folder 10)
        - Giorgione, circa 1950s (Box 344, Folder 11)
        - Gogh, Vincent van, 1940s-1980s, (2 Folders) (Box 344, Folder 12 to 13)
          (File 13 is accompanied by a German publication on Vincent van Gogh)
        - Gottlieb, Adolph, 1974 (Box 345, Folder 1)
        - Goya, Francisco de, 1940s-1980s, (2 Folders) (Box 345, Folder 2 to 3)
        - Graffiti, 1970s (Box 345, Folder 4)
        - Graubard, Mark, 1937 (Box 345, Folder 5)
        - Greco, El, 1950s (Box 345, Folder 6)
        - Gros, Antoine-Jean, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 345, Folder 7)
        - Grünewald, Matthias, 1930s-1960s (Box 345, Folder 8)
        - Hagia Sophia (Church: Iznik, Turkey), circa 1930s (Box 345, Folder 9)
        - Heschel, Abraham Joshua, 1951 (Box 345, Folder 10)
        - Hiberno-Saxon iconography, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 345, Folder 11)
        - History -- Periodization, 1950s-1960s (Box 345, Folder 12)
        - Hodler, Ferdinand, 1940s (Box 345, Folder 13)
        - Hook, Sidney, 1934-1994 (Box 345, Folder 14)
        - Humanism, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 345, Folder 15)
        - Hume, David, circa 1930s (Box 345, Folder 16)
        - Iconography -- Irish, circa 1960s (Box 345, Folder 17)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - Armenia -- Ejmiatsin, 1930s-1950s (Box 346, Folder 1)
          - Austria -- Vienna, 1930s (Box 346, Folder 2)
          - Ashburnham Pentateuch, 1930s-1950s, (6 Folders) (Box 346, Folder 3 to 8)
          - Astronomical, 1940s-1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 346, Folder 9 to 10)
          - Belgium, 1930s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 346, Folder 11 to 12)
          - Biblioteca apostolica vaticana, circa 1950s (Box 346, Folder 13)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - Bibliothèque de l'Arsenal, 1930s-1950s (Box 347, Folder 1)
          - Bibliothèque Mazarine, 1930s-1950s (Box 347, Folder 2)
          - Bibliothèque nationale de France, lists, 1926-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 347, Folder 3 to 4)
          - Bibliothèque nationale de France, 1926-1960s, (5 Folders) (Box 347, Folder 5 to 9)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - Bibliothèque nationale de France, 1926-1950s, (16 Folders) (Box 348, Folder 1 to 16)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - Bibliothèque nationale de France, 1926-1950s (Box 349, Folder 1 to 3)
          - Bodleian Library, 1960s, (3 Folders) (Box 349, Folder 4 to 6)
          - British Museum, 1930s, (2 Folders) (Box 349, Folder 7 to 8)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - British Museum, 1930s-1940s, (4 Folders) (Box 350, Folder 1 to 4)
          - Byzantine, 1930s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 350, Folder 5 to 6)
          - Carolingian, 1930s-1960s (Box 350, Folder 7)
          - Carolingian -- Ada school, 1930s-1960s (Box 350, Folder 8)
          - Carolingian -- Corbie school, 1930s-1960s (Box 350, Folder 9)
          - Carolingian -- Franco-Saxon school, 1930s-1960s (Box 350, Folder 10)
          - Codex Amiatinus, 1930s-1950s (Box 350, Folder 11)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - Corpus Christi College (University of Cambridge), 1930s-1950s (Box 351, Folder 1)
          - Correspondence, 1950s (Box 351, Folder 2)
          - Early Christian, 1930s (Box 351, Folder 3)
          - Early Christian, Syria, 1930s (Box 351, Folder 4)
          - England, 1930s-1960s (Box 351, Folder 5)
          - European libraries -- Lists, 1930s-1950s (Box 351, Folder 6)
          - France, 1930s-1960s, (8 Folders) (Box 351, Folder 7 to 14)
          - France -- Aix, 1930s-1960s (Box 351, Folder 15)
          - France -- Albi, 1930s-1960s (Box 351, Folder 16)
          - France -- Amiens, 1930s-1960s (Box 351, Folder 17)
          - France -- Angers, 1930s-1960s (Box 351, Folder 18)
          - France -- Auxerre, 1930s-1960s, (7 Folders) (Box 351, Folder 19 to 25)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - France -- Auxerre, 1940s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 1)
          - France -- Cluny, 1930s-1960s, (3 Folders) (Box 352, Folder 2 to 4)
          - France -- Grenoble, 1930s-1960s (Box 352, Folder 5)
          - France -- Libraries, 1930s-1950 (Box 352, Folder 6)
          - France -- Lyon, 1930s-1960s (Box 352, Folder 7)
          - France -- Metz, 1930s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 8)
          - France -- Moissac, 1930s-1950s, (3 Folders) (Box 352, Folder 9 to 11)
          - France -- Montpellier, 1930s-1960s (Box 352, Folder 12)
          - France -- Nantes and Nimes, 1930s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 13)
          - France -- Orleans, 1930s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 14)
          - France -- Provence, 1930s (Box 352, Folder 15)
          - France -- Reims, 1930s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 16)
          - France -- South, 1930s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 17)
          - France -- Verdun, 1930s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 18)
          - Germany, 1930s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 352, Folder 19 to 20)
          - Germany -- Fulda, 1930s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 21)
          - Germany -- Reichenau (Baden-Württemberg), 1930s-1950s (Box 352, Folder 22)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - Golden Gospels of Henry VIII, 1930s-1950s (Box 353, Folder 1)
          - Gothic, 1930s (Box 353, Folder 2)
          - Hiberno-Saxon, 1930s-1960s (Box 353, Folder 3)
          - Holland, 1930s (Box 353, Folder 4)
          - Ireland, circa 1940s-1950s, (3 Folders) (Box 353, Folder 5 to 7)
          - Islamic, 1950s (Box 353, Folder 8)
          - Italy, 1930s-1950s, (5 Folders) (Box 353, Folder 9 to 13)
          - Kloster St. Gallen, 1930s-1950s (Box 353, Folder 14)
          - Library collections -- Lists, 1930s-1950s (Box 353, Folder 15)
          - Medieval, 1930s-1950s (Box 353, Folder 16)
        - Illumination of books and manuscripts
          - Medieval, 1930s-1980s, (4 Folders) (Box 354, Folder 1 to 4)
          - Merovingian, 1930s-1960s (Box 354, Folder 5)
          - Newberry Library, 1940s-1960s (Box 354, Folder 6)
          - New York Public Library, 1930s-1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 354, Folder 7 to 8)
          - Ottonian, 1930s-1960s, (2 Folders) (Box 354, Folder 9 to 10)
          - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1940s-1960s, (5 Folders) (Box 354, Folder 11 to 15)
          - Quedlinburg Itala, 1930s (Box 354, Folder 16)
          - Romanesque, 1930s-1950s, (3 Folders) (Box 354, Folder 17 to 19)
          - Spain, 1930s-1960s, (3 Folders) (Box 354, Folder 20 to 22)
          - Switzerland, 1939s-1950s (Box 354, Folder 23)
          - University of Michigan, 1940s-1960s (Box 354, Folder 24)
          - Vergilius Vaticanus, 1930s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 354, Folder 25 to 26)
          - Walters Art Museum (Baltimore, MD), 1940s-1960s (Box 354, Folder 27)
        - Impressionism (Art), 1960s-1980s, (7 Folders) (Box 355, Folder 1 to 7)
        - Individualism -- Artists, 1930s (Box 355, Folder 8)
        - Ingres, Jean-August-Dominique, 1940s (Box 355, Folder 9)
        - Interpretation (Philosophy), 1930s-1950s (Box 355, Folder 10)
        - Islamic architecture, circa 1930s (Box 356, Folder 1)
        - Jakobson, Roman, 1960s-1970s, (2 Folders) (Box 356, Folder 2 to 3)
        - Jewish art, 1930s-1960s (Box 356, Folder 4)
        - Joyce, James, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 356, Folder 5)
        - Judgment and valuation, circa 1960s, (4 Folders) (Box 356, Folder 6 to 9)
        - Kandinsky, Vassily, 1960s (Box 356, Folder 10)
        - Klee, Paul, 1954 (Box 356, Folder 11)
        - Kornacki, Jerzy, 1961-1962 (Box 356, Folder 12)
        - Kracauer, Siegfried, 1990s (Box 356, Folder 13)